Greenway Productions Records
Greenway Productions Records
1965-1968
Greenway Productions
9 linear ft.
Scripts for television and movie productions by Greenway Productions, including those for the television series Batman (1965-1967), The Green Hornet (1966-1967), The Loner (1965-1966), The Tammy Grimes Show (1966) and for the film The Big Bounce; also includes taped lectures by William Dozier (1967-1968).
149021
Scope and Contents of the Collection
Greenway Productions Records contains scripts from four of producer William Dozier's Greenway Productions television shows: Batman (Nov 1965-Dec 1967); The Green Hornet (Jun 1966- Jan 1967); The Loner (Jun 1965-Dec 1966); and The Tammy Grimes Show (Jun-Oct 1966). All the scripts are final and revised drafts of the weekly episodes and are the most original scripts available from the producers. The scripts are arranged alphabetically by program title and within each season alphabetically by script title.
The collection also contains a number of scripts related to production of the film adaptation of Elmore Leonard's novel The Big Bounce. The screenplay was written by Robert Dozier (son of William Dozier), and the 1969 film starred Ryan O'Neal, Leigh Taylor-Young and Van Hefflin. There are multiple versions of the script, reflecting the process of production, including an initial treatment of the novel, the first draft, the estimating draft (and production budget), the final screenplay and the screenplay as filmed. The collection also contains another Robert Dozier penned screenplay, an adaptation of the 1928 novel The Well of Lonliness by Radclyffe Hall. This film was not realized.
In addition to the written manuscripts, there are 32 reel-to-reel audio recordings of lectures given by executive producer and Greenway Productions' founder, William Dozier. Some of these recordings stem from a U.C.L.A. course taught by Dozier, Network Television: The Facts of Life (Theater Arts XL 198A), a course documented in a Time magazine article of 29 Mar 1968. It is not known if all of the taped lectures derive from this particular course. Dozier's lecture spots often featured prominent guests from the television industry, including John H. Mitchell, president of Columbia Pictures television division, Edward Bleier, senior executive at ABC television, and television producer and founder of MTM, Grant Tinker.
Subject and Genre Headings
Radio, television, film; Popular culture; Greenway Productions.; Dozier, Robert.; Dozier, William.; Batman (Television program: 1966-1968); Big bounce (Motion picture: 1969); Green Hornet (Television program); The Loner (Television program); The Tammy Grimes show (Television program); Fantasy television programs.; Motion picture plays, American.; Television scripts.; Television series -- United States.; Television programs.; Lectures.; Screenplays.; Television scripts.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Greenway Productions.
Inventory
- Television productions
  - Batman
    - 1965 - 1966 Season
      - The Bookworm Turns, 14 Feb 1966; (2cs) final script (Box 1)
      - The Curse of Tut, 28 Feb 1966; (2cs) final script (Box 1)
      - Death in Slow Motion, 7 Mar 1966; (2cs) final script (Box 1)
      - Mr. Freeze, 26 Nov 1965; (2cs) final script (Box 1)
      - Fine Feathered Finks, 19 Nov 1965; (2cs) final script (Box 1)
      - Fine Finny Fiends, 25 Mar 1966; (2cs) final script (Box 1)
      - Hi Diddle Riddle, 3 Sep 1965; revised draft (Box 2)
      - The Joker Goes to School, 13 Dec 1965; (2cs) final (Box 2)
      - The Joker is Wild, 8 Dec 1965; (2cs) final (Box 2)
      - The Joker Trumps on Ace, 21 Feb 1966; (2cs) final script (Box 2)
      - The Penguin Goes Straight, 7 Feb 1966; revised final script (Box 2)
      - Pilot Script, 3 Sep 1965; revised draft (Box 2)
      - The Purrfect Crime, 26 Jan 1966; (2cs) final script (Box 2)
      - A Riddle a Day Keeps the Riddler Away, 28 Dec 1965; (2cs) revised final script (Box 3)
      - The Ring of Wax, 9 Feb 1966; (2cs) final script (Box 3)
      - The Thirteenth Hat, 14 Jan 1966; (2cs) final script (Box 3)
      - True or False Face, 5 Jan 1966; (2cs) final script (Box 3)
      - Zelda the Great, 23 Nov 1965; (2cs) revised draft (Box 3)
    - 1966 - 1967 Season
      - Batman's Anniversary, 27 Dec 1966; final (Box 4)
      - Black Widow strikes Again, 8 Feb 1967; revised final (Box 4)
      - The Cat's Meow revised, 7 Nov 1966; final script (Box 4)
      - Catwoman Goes to College, 16 Jan 1967; final script (Box 4)
      - The Clock King's Crazy Crimes, 20 July 1966; revised final script (Box 4)
      - Come Back, Shame, 3 Oct 1966; final script (Box 4)
      - The Contaminated Cow, 23 Nov 1966; final script (Box 4)
      - The Devil's Fingers, 9 Sep 1966; final script (Box 4)
      - An Egg Grows in Gotham, 11 Aug 1966; final script (Box 4)
      - The Greatest Mother of Them All, 9 Aug 1966; final script (Box 5)
      - Green Ice revised, 20 Sept 1966; final script (Box 5)
      - Hizzonner the Penguin, 31 Aug 1966; final script (Box 5)
      - Hot Off the Griddle, 9 May 1966; final script (Box 5)
      - Ice Spy, 27 Feb 1967; final script (Box 5)
      - The Impractical Joker, 7 Sep 1966; final script (Box 5)
      - The Jokers Last Laugh, 9 Jan 1967; final script (Box 5)
      - King Tut's Coup, 1 Feb 1967; final script (Box 5)
      - Marsha, Queen of Diamonds, 23 Sep 1966; final script (Box 5)
      - The Minstrel's Shakedown, 29 Jul 1966; revised final script (Box 5)
      - Penguin is a Girl's Best Friend, 30 Nov 1966; final script (Box 6)
      - The Penguin's Nest, 9 Jun 1966; final script (Box 6)
      - A Piece of Action, 24 Jan 1967; final script (Box 6)
      - Pop Goes the Joker, 10 Feb 1967; final script (Box 6)
      - The Puzzles are Coming, 17 Oct 1966; revised final script (Box 6)
      - The Sandman Cometh, 7 Nov 1966; revised final (Box 6)
      - Shoot a Crooked Arrow, 29 Jun 1966; revised final script (Box 6)
      - The Spell of Tut, 13 Jul 1966; sec. revised final script (Box 6)
      - That Darn Catwoman, 12 Dec 1966; final script (Box 6)
      - The Zodiac Crimes, 26 Oct 1966; revised final script (Box 6)
    - 1967 - 1968 Season
      - Catwoman's Dressed to Kill, 18 Oct 1967; first draft (Box 7)
      - Catwoman's Dressed to Kill, 24 Oct 1967; final script (Box 7)
      - Catwoman's Dressed to Kill, revised pages and shooting schedule (Box 7)
      - The Entrancing Dr. Cassandra, 27 Nov 1967; final script (Box 7)
      - The Entrancing Dr. Cassandra, revised pages and shooting schedule (Box 7)
      - The Great Escape, 20 Nov 1967; first draft (Box 7)
      - The Great Escape, 28 Nov 1967; final draft (Box 7)
      - The Great Escape, revised pages and shooting schedule (Box 7)
      - I'll be a Mummy's Uncle, 7 Dec 1967; final script (Box 7)
      - I'll be a Mummy's Uncle, 11 Dec 1967; revised final (Box 7)
      - I'll be a Mummy's Uncle, revised pages and shooting schedule (Box 7)
      - The Joker's Flying Saucer, 14 Nov 1967; final (Box 7)
      - The Joker's Flying Saucer, revised pages and shooting schedule (Box 7)
      - Minerva, Mayhem and Millionaires, 5 Dec 1967; first draft (Box 7)
      - Minerva, Mayhem and Millionaires, 13 Dec 1967; final (Box 7)
      - Minerva, Mayhem and Millionaires, 15 Dec 1967; revised final (Box 7)
      - Minerva, Mayhem and Millionaires, revised pages and shooting schedule (Box 7)
      - Nora Clavicle and the Ladies Crime Club, 6 Nov 1967; first draft (Box 8)
      - Nora Clavicle and the Ladies Crime Club, 7 Nov 1967; revised draft (Box 8)
      - Nora Clavicle and the Ladies Crime Club, 9 Nov 1967; final draft (Box 8)
      - Nora Clavicle and the Ladies Crime Club, revised pages and shooting schedule (Box 8)
      - Penguin's Clean Sweep, 16 Nov 1967; first draft (Box 8)
      - Penguin's Clean Sweep, 24 Nov 1967; final draft (Box 8)
      - Penguin's Clean Sweep, shooting schedule (Box 8)
  - The Green Hornet, 1966 - 1967 Season
    - Ace in the Hole, 28 Nov 1966; (2cs) final draft (Box 9)
    - Alias "the scarf", 14 Dec 1966; (2cs) final draft (Box 9)
    - Bad Bet on a 459--Silent, 2 Dec 1966; (2cs) final draft (Box 9)
    - Beautiful Dreamer, 30 Aug 1966; revised final draft (Box 9)
    - Crime Wave, 14 Jun 1966; (2cs) final draft (Box 9)
    - Corpse of the Year, 16 Nov 1966; (2cs) final draft (Box 9)
    - Deadline for Death, 27 Sep 1966; (2cs) final draft (Box 9)
    - Eat Drink and be Dead, 9 Aug 1966; (2cs) final draft (Box 9)
    - Freeway to Death, 27 Oct 1966; (2cs) final (Box 10)
    - The Frog is a Deadly Weapon, 19 Jul 1966; final (Box 10)
    - Give 'em Enough Rope, 22 Jul 1966; final (Box 10)
    - The Hornet and the Firefly, 8 Nov 1966; final (Box 10)
    - Hornet Save Thyself, 30 Dec 1966; final (Box 10)
    - The Hunters and the Hunted, 20 Sep 1966; final (Box 10)
    - Invasion from Outer Space, 6 Jan 1967; final draft (Box 10)
    - May the Best Man Lose, 12 Oct 1966; final draft (Box 10)
    - The Preying Mantis, 15 Sep 1966; (2cs) revised final (Box 11)
    - Programmed for Death, 3 Jun 1966; (2cs) revised final (Box 11)
    - The Ray is for Killing, 1 Aug 1966; (2cs) final (Box 11)
    - The Secret of the Sally Bell, 5 Oct 1966; final (Box 11)
    - Seek, Stalk, and Destroy, 4 Nov 1966; (2cs) final (Box 11)
    - The Silent Gun, 6 Jul 1966; (2cs) revised final (Box 11)
    - Trouble for Prince Charming, 7 Dec 1966; (2cs) final (Box 11)
  - The Loner, 1965 - 1966 Season
    - The Burden of the Badge, 20 Dec 1966; revised final (Box 12)
    - An Echo of Bugles, 11 Jun 1965; final (Box 12)
    - Escort for a Dead Man, 15 Oct 1965; revised final (Box 12)
    - The Flight of the Arctic Tern, 15 Jun 1965; final (Box 12)
    - The Homecoming of Lemuel Stove, 9 Jun 1965; final (Box 12)
    - The House Rules at Mrs. Wayne, 8 Jun 1965; final (Box 12)
    - Hunt the Man Down, 16 Jun 1965; final (Box 12)
    - Incident in the Middle of Nowhere, 26 Nov 1965; final (Box 12)
    - The Kingdom of the McComb, 18 Jun 1965; final draft (Box 12)
    - A Little Stroll to the End of the Line, 18 Nov 1965; 2nd revised final (Box 12)
    - The Lonely Calico Queen, 17 Jun 1965; final (Box 12)
    - Mantrap shooting, 18 Oct 1965; final (Box 12)
    - The Mourners for Johnny Sharp, 5 Nov 1965; first draft (Box 12)
    - The Mourners for Johnny Sharp, 18 Jun 1965; final draft (Box 12)
    - The Oath, 10 Jun 1965; final (Box 13)
    - One of the Wounded, 17 Jun 1965; final (Box 13)
    - The Ordeal of Bud Windom, 17 Aug 1965; revised final (Box 13)
    - Pick Me Another Time to Die, 1 Dec 1965; revised final (Box 13)
    - A Question of Guilt, 5 Nov 1965; revised final (Box 13)
    - The Sherrif of Fetterman's Crossing, 9 Aug 1965; revised final (Box 13)
    - To Hang a Dead Man, 18 Nov 1965; first draft (Box 13)
    - To the West of Eden, 23 Jun 1965; final draft (Box 13)
    - The Trial in Paradise, 2 Nov 1965; second revised final (Box 13)
    - The Vespers, 18 Jun 1965; final (Box 13)
    - Westward the Showmaker, 10 Jun 1965; final draft (Box 13)
    - Savage on the Evening Stage, 18 Jun 1965; final draft (Box 13)
  - The Tammy Grimes Show, 1966 - 1967 Season
    - Diamonds Are a Bird's Best Friend, 16 Aug 1966; final (Box 14)
    - A Funny Thing Happened on the Way to the Studio, 25 Aug 1966; final draft (Box 14)
    - George Washington Didn't Sleep Here, 5 Aug 1966; revised final draft (Box 14)
    - Give Her Back to the Indians, 13 Jun 1966; first draft (Box 14)
    - The Great Charge Account Way, 12 Sep 1966; final draft (Box 14)
    - He's No Sandy Koufax, But I'll Buy Him, 13 Sep 1966; revised final (Box 14)
    - How to Steal A Girl Even If It's Only Me, 14 Jun 1966; revised final (Box 14)
    - It's in the Bag, Dad, 7 Sep 1966; final draft (Box 14)
    - Officer's Mess, 29 June 1966; final (Box 14)
    - Pilot Script, 18 Oct 1965; revised final (Box 14)
    - Positively Made in Paris, 13 Jul 1966; fourth revised final draft (Box 14)
    - Send a Rich Girl to Camp This Summer, 29 Jul 1966; revised final draft (Box 14)
    - The Ski's the Limit, 16 Jun 1966; final draft (Box 14)
    - Tamantha Nightingale Rides Again, 23 Aug 1966; revised final (Box 14)
    - Tommy's Hits Las Vegas, or Vice Versa, 1 Jul 1966; second revised final (Box 14)
    - Tammy Plays Cupid, 31 Aug 1966; revised final (Box 14)
- Motion Picture Productions
  - The Big Bounce, screenplay by Robert Dozier; based on the novel by Elmore Leonard, 1968
    - Manuscript of original novel [typewritten copy] (Box 18)
    - Screenwriters scene breakdown of novel (Box 18)
    - First draft screenplay (Box 18)
    - Studio estimating first draft (estimating script), 25 Jan 1968 (Box 18)
    - Final draft screenplay (pre-shooting), 29 Apr 1968 (Box 18)
    - Final screenplay as filmed, 29 Apr-3 Sep 1968 (Box 18)
    - All page changes in chronological order up to final screenplay as filmed, Mar-Aug 1968 (Box 18)
    - Script memos (Box 18)
    - Budget and Revised Budget (Box 18)
  - The Well of Loneliness, screenplay by Robert Dozier; from the novel by Radclyffe Hall, 25 Nov 1968
    - Estimating script [typewritten copy] (Box 15)
- Lectures by William Dozier (audiorecordings)
  - 1967 Lectures, Some tapes note "Haines Hall 213"; lectures recorded on 1/4 inch magnetic tape at 3-3/4 ips
    - Lecture 1 (Parts 1-2), 9 Jan 1967 (Box 16)
    - Lecture 2 (Parts 1-2), 16 Jan 1967 (Box 16)
    - Lecture 3 (Parts 1-2), Guest: Harve Bennet ABC, 23 Jan 1967 (Box 16)
    - Lecture 4 (Parts 1-2), Guest: David Levy, 30 Jan 1967 (Box 16)
    - Lecture 5 (Part 1), 6 Feb 1967 (Box 16)
    - Lecture 5 (Part 2), 6 Feb 1967 (Box 16)
    - Lecture 6 (Sides 1-2), Guest: John Mitchell, 13 Feb 1967 (Box 16)
    - Lecture 7, 20 Feb 1967 (Box 16)
    - Lecture 8, 27 Feb 1967 (Box 16)
    - Lecture 9, Guest: Ed Bleier ABC-TV, 6 Mar 1967 (Box 16)
    - Lecture 10, 13 Mar 1967 (Box 16)
  - 1968 Lectures, Lectures recorded on 1/4 inch magnetic tape at 3-3/4 ips.
    - Lecture 1, 8 Jan 1968 (Box 17)
    - Lecture 2, Dozier and Tinker, 15 Jan 1968 (Box 17)
    - Lecture 3, 22 Jan 1968 (Box 17)
    - Lecture 4, Guest: Nicholas Johnson, 29 Jan 1968 (Box 17)
    - Lecture 5, Dozier and Levy, 5 Feb 1968 (Box 17)
    - Lecture 6, Dozier and Ackerman, 12 Feb 1968 (Box 17)
    - Lecture 7, Guest: John Mitchell, 19 Feb 1968 (Box 17)
    - Lecture 8, Lee Rich, [26 Feb 1968] (Box 17)
    - Lecture 9, Guest: Stromberg, 4 Mar 1968 (Box 17)
    - Lecture 10, 11 Mar 1968 (Box 17)
    - Lecture 11, 18 Mar 1968 (Box 17)
  - 1968 Lectures (Arts and Humanities Extension), Lectures recorded on 1/4 inch magnetic tape at 3-3/4 ips
    - Lecture 1, No Guest, 7 Oct 1968 (Box 15)
    - Lecture 2, No Guest, 14 Oct 1968 (Box 15)
    - Lecture 3, Guest: Kenneth Cox, 21 Oct 1968 (Box 15)
    - Lecture 4, Guest: Alan Wagner, 28 Oct 1968 (Box 15)
    - Lecture 5, Guest: Roy Higgins, 4 Nov 1968 (Box 15)
    - Lecture 6, Guest: John Mitchell, 11 Nov 1968 (Box 15)
    - Lecture 7, Guest: Jim Aubrey (one side), 18 Nov 1968 (Box 15)
    - Lecture 8, Guest: D. Cramer (side one, after 10-15 minutes, is distorted. Side 2 ok), 25 Nov 1968 (Box 15)
    - Lecture 9, Guest: Herb Schlosser, 2 Dec 1968 (Box 15)
    - Lecture 10, No Guest, 10 Dec 1968 (Box 15)